drapersonline.com 2014-06-30

# 

## 1\. Introduction

  1. This Privacy and Cookies Policy sets out the privacy policy of Emap Publishing Limited, Company Number 7880758 (England) whose registered address is c/o Top Right Group Limited, The Prow, 1 Wilder Walk, London W1B 5AP (”Emap”), who controls this website. For the purpose of the Data Protection Act, the data controller is Emap Publishing Limited. 
  2. Emap is committed to protecting the privacy of its users and the purpose of this Privacy Policy is to describe to you how Emap will use personal information about you that is submitted to Emap.
  3. By providing your personal information to Emap, you consent to the collection and use of it and any other information provided to Emap in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If at any time you wish to change the uses of your personal information to which you have consented, please contact us at security@emap.com. 
  4. Emap may revise this Privacy Policy at any time by posting an update on its website(s). Please ensure that you check this website and any other Emap website(s) you use from time to time to review the then current Privacy Policy and to update your preferences. This Privacy and Cookies Policy was last updated in January 2013.

## 2\. Collection of Personal Information

  1. The types of personal information collected and stored by Emap might include your name, date of birth, e-mail address, postal address, telephone number, fax number and credit/debit card details (to the extent permitted by the Data Protection Act 1998 and related legislation (“the DPA”). 
  2. Emap (or any of its sub-contractors) may collect personal information about you in the following ways:   
a. any data which you provide when you complete and submit an application to Emap to register on its website(s) or receive email alerts or other communications from Emap;   
b. any data that you provide via postings to forums and blogs and any other posting that you make to a Emap website (in such circumstances the information posted by you will, of course, also be available to users of the website throughout the world);   
c. during any transaction with us; and   
d. any other data which you provide to Emap when you enquire about our activities, email, telephone or write to us or otherwise provide us with personal information.   

  3. Emap (or any of its sub-contractors) may also receive information about you from third parties, for example a friend who wants to tell you about one of our websites.

## 3\. Storage and retention of your information

  1. Emap will keep your information on a secure server. The technology that Emap uses and the security policies which Emap has implemented are intended to safeguard your information from unauthorised access and improper use. 
  2. Emap will keep your information (to the extent permitted by the DPA) to enable Emap to use it for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

## 4\. Use of Your Information

  1. Emap may use your personal information (subject in each case to the requirements of the DPA) for the following purposes:   
a. administering your website account(s) and otherwise in connection with any service for which you have provided your information, including any email alerts, transactions with us and competitions and promotions that you take part in;   
b. responding to any enquiry you make;   
c. subject to your consent, sending you newsletters and/or alerts and information regarding Emap's or any third party's future services (in all formats to which you have consented eg post, email, text); and   
d. for generating aggregated statistics about users, traffic patterns etc of the Emap website(s) and other services and developing Emap's marketing plans. 
  2. Emap may also disclose your information (subject in each case to the requirements of the DPA) as follows:   
a. if you have given your consent for Emap to do so, to other selected organisations to enable them to contact you or send you information by post, telephone and/or email;   
b. to any service providers, sub-contractors and agents appointed by Emap to perform the above functions on its behalf and in accordance with its instructions;   
c. to third parties selected by Emap as part of aggregated and anonymised statistics about users, traffic patterns etc of the Emap website(s);   
d. to such individuals and/or bodies as necessary to ensure Emap's compliance with any applicable law, regulation, legal proceeding or governmental request;   
e. (where you post material that does or may constitute a criminal offence, breach the rights of a third party, give rise to a civil action or breach the Terms & Conditions of the applicable website and as otherwise necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Emap and its customers), to any relevant authority or third party requiring Emap to disclose the identity of or locate anyone posting such material on an Emap website; and   
f. to any individual making a subject information request to Emap.
  3. In the event that Emap (or a relevant part of Emap) is acquired by or merges with another company, your personal information may be passed to the purchasing/merging company amongst the transferred business assets. This will enable your relationship to continue with the relevant Emap business despite the change of ownership. Your personal information may also be passed (on a confidential basis) to companies with whom Emap is negotiating such a sale/merger as part of the verification exercise carried out on Emap by the third party. 
  4. In processing your information in accordance with the above, Emap may (to the extent permitted by the DPA) send it outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). Emap will take all reasonable steps to ensure that in such circumstances your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy but your attention is drawn to the fact that the laws of countries outside the EEA may provide lesser protection to your information than the UK. When you submit your personal information to Emap you consent to the transfer of your information outside the EEA unless you specifically indicate otherwise.

## 5\. Cookies

When you visit an Emap website(s), Emap uses “cookie” technology try to make that experience simple, personalised and meaningful. Cookies are small pieces of information which are issued to your computer or any similar device you use to access the internet e.g. smart phone, tablet or other mobile device when you visit a website and which store and sometimes track information about you're use of the website. A number of cookies Emap use last only for the duration of your web session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the website and will last for longer.

Emap use cookies to:

  * create a specific log-in session for a visitor to an Emap website in order that page requests by that visitor are delivered in an effective, secure and consistent manner; 
  * recognise when a visitor to a Emap website has visited before; this means we can identify the number of unique visitors we receive to the website and allows us to make sure we have enough capacity for the number of users that we get; 
  * customise elements of the promotional layout and/or content of the pages of the website; 
  * store your product selections to the shopping basket; 
  * collect statistical information about how our visitors use the website(s) so that we can improve the website(s) and learn which parts are most popular to visitors; and 
  * Gather information through our advertising partners, about the pages on the Emap website(s) that you visit, and also other information about other websites that you visit, so as to place you in an “interest segment”. This information is then used to serve interest-based advertisements which it is believed will be targeted to your interests. For more information about this type of interest based advertising, and about how to turn this feature off please visit www.youronlinechoices.co.uk or follow the link to the website of our advertising partners shown below. Without these cookies, advertisements you encounter will be less relevant to you and to your interests. 

Some of the cookies used by Emap websites are set by us, and some are set by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser. Please note however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used on an Emap website(s) you may not be able to take full advantage of the website(s) if you do so.

  * Our cookies 

We have described the main cookies we use and what we use these for below: 

Cookie name | Purpose  
---|---  
ARPT | This is a technical session cookie set by our website to share the number of visitors we get on our site between web servers. This is so the site does not get overloaded and can perform at its optimum potential.  
ASP.NET_SESSIONId | This session cookie tells us that you are actively using our site. This way we can always know, at any given time, how many users we have visiting.  
SSOEX_[ID] | This tells us whether you are logged into our site  
emapauth | This cookie supports the linking of subscriptions between our different products  
tempid | Similar to the emapauth cookie, this supports the linking of subscriptions between our different products  
.ASPXAUTH | This cookie is used to store an encryption key of the users authentication after login so that they remain authenticated during their session on the website  

  * Third party cookies

Certain cookies are either set by third parties on the Website or these are set by us using the third parties cookie code. More information about cookies placed by third parties and how to restrict or block their cookies can be accessed by following the link to their website. In addition to cookies, tracking gifs may be set by us or third parties in respect of your use of the Site. Tracking gifs are small image files within the content of our site or the body of our newsletters so we or third parties can understand which parts of the website are visited or whether particular content is of interest. 

Cookie name | Purpose | More Information  
---|---|---  
Adtech | Adtech is EMAP's online ad server used for serving and tracking advertisements across the EMAP websites | [Adtech Cookie opt-out](http://www.adtech.com/cookie_opt-out)  
Webtrends   
WT.FPC | WebTrends uses a cookie to track the number of unique users of this website. It basically tells us whether the website has a small number of regular visitors or a large number of infrequent visitors. The cookie only relates to what goes on in this website | [WebTrends Privacy Policy](http://webtrends.com/privacy-statement/)  
Google Analytics   
_utma   
_utmb   
_utmc   
_utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
comScore | Comscore help us to provide online surveys and video content through our Site. Comscore use cookies so that they can provide anonymous statistics on the interaction of users with these online surveys or video content. | [comScore Privacy Policy](http://www.comscore.com/About_comScore/Privacy_Policy)  
AddThis | AddThis helps us to integrate social media sharing tools into our website such as facebook or twitter and to measure the effectiveness of these sharing tools | [AddThis opt-out](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out#.T3FyoHmx2Sp)  
DoubleClick (Google) | Doubleclick use a cookie when they serve advertisements in order that they can deliver reports on the effectiveness of these advertisements on our Site. The cookie records what advertisements the user has seen and how often | [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy/ads/)  
Optify   
_opt_gvi | Optify collects information about End User activity on the Site, including a unique Optify Customer ID, the End User’s IP address, the URL of the “referring” Web page (i.e., the page viewed by the End User prior to visiting the tracked page on your Site), the title and URL of tracked pages on the Site, and information about pages visited and actions taken. The Javascript code makes a “call” to our Software Services where, relying on third party service providers, we use the IP address to identify company name and approximate geographical location for the End User. | [Optify Privacy Policy](http://www.optify.net/about-our-b2b-inbound-marketing-solutions/privacy)  

## 6\. Third Party Websites

Please be aware that Emap does not control and is not responsible for websites that are referred to or linked from its own websites and that use of your personal information on these websites is not subject to this Privacy and Cookies Policy.

## 7\. Registration

  1. To access certain parts of the Emap websites, Emap may require you to register and provide certain information about yourself.
  2. You are reminded that in addition to the provisions of this Privacy and Cookies Policy, where you register you also agree to:   
a. provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself as prompted by the relevant registration form (such information being the "Registration Data"); and   
b. maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it fully up to date.
